<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hvm on Kev&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://www.kevssite.com/tags/hvm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hvm on Kev&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.kevssite.com/tags/hvm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting a XEN DOMU from HVM to PV</title>
      <link>http://www.kevssite.com/converting-a-xen-domu-from-hvm-to-pv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.kevssite.com/converting-a-xen-domu-from-hvm-to-pv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For distros that don’t support XEN compatible installers the easiest way to create a PV (ParaVirtual) DOMU is to install as a HVM (see my other article entry for this) ad then once installed, convert it to a PV DOMU.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons why you might want to go with PV instead of HVM. The main two that spring to mind are PV’s offer better performance/lower overhead and PV DOMU’s allow PCI passthrough. Although apparently XEN 3.4 can now do PCI passthrough with HVM, as long as you have an Intel chip with vt-d.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article will start off where my previous “Installing a XEN hvm DOMU” left off…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing a XEN hvm DOMU</title>
      <link>http://www.kevssite.com/installing-a-xen-hvm-domu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.kevssite.com/installing-a-xen-hvm-domu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this to work your CPU and motherboard needs to support vt (intel) or amd-v. You can check this by looking at the flags in /proc/cpuinfo. Your looking for either vmx or svm on the flags line.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re doing this from your DOM0 then these flags may not actually show up. Instead type &lt;code&gt;xm info&lt;/code&gt; and look for ‘hvm’ on the virt_caps line.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my hvm install, i’ll be installing Ubuntu 9.04 Desktop Linux.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I have copied the live CD ISO onto my XEN DOM0 and will be installing directly from the iso rather than burning the CD. I have also created a 10GB LVM logical volume to act as the disk for my new DOMU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
