<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xen on Kev&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://www.kevssite.com/categories/xen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Xen on Kev&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.kevssite.com/categories/xen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Xen 4.1 released</title>
      <link>http://www.kevssite.com/xen-4-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.kevssite.com/xen-4-1-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today saw the release of Xen 4.1. Major changes include support for greater than 255 CPUs, a new credit scheduler and CPU pools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the most significant change to those that use Xen will be the new XL toolstack which replaces XM/XEND and will ultimately replace xcp’s xapi and libvirt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XEN DOM0 support in mainline kernel at last!</title>
      <link>http://www.kevssite.com/xen-dom0-in-mainline-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.kevssite.com/xen-dom0-in-mainline-kernel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The XEN developers ad community have been trying fr years to get DOM0 support into the Linux mainline kernel. On January 5th 2011 it finally happened when Linux kernel 2.6.37 was released.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Okay, so it’s only basic support at this stage, but it does represent a significant milestone in the hypervisors history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mounting LVM backed XEN disk partitions in DOM0</title>
      <link>http://www.kevssite.com/mounting-lvm-backed-xen-disk-partitions-in-dom0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.kevssite.com/mounting-lvm-backed-xen-disk-partitions-in-dom0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you might need to mount a DOMU’s disk in DOM0, so that you can edit files, or even recover them in the event that your DOMU is broken and fails to boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting a XEN DOMU from HVM to PV</title>
      <link>http://www.kevssite.com/converting-a-xen-domu-from-hvm-to-pv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.kevssite.com/converting-a-xen-domu-from-hvm-to-pv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For distros that don’t support XEN compatible installers the easiest way to create a PV (ParaVirtual) DOMU is to install as a HVM (see my other article entry for this) ad then once installed, convert it to a PV DOMU.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons why you might want to go with PV instead of HVM. The main two that spring to mind are PV’s offer better performance/lower overhead and PV DOMU’s allow PCI passthrough. Although apparently XEN 3.4 can now do PCI passthrough with HVM, as long as you have an Intel chip with vt-d.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article will start off where my previous “Installing a XEN hvm DOMU” left off…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing a XEN hvm DOMU</title>
      <link>http://www.kevssite.com/installing-a-xen-hvm-domu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.kevssite.com/installing-a-xen-hvm-domu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this to work your CPU and motherboard needs to support vt (intel) or amd-v. You can check this by looking at the flags in /proc/cpuinfo. Your looking for either vmx or svm on the flags line.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re doing this from your DOM0 then these flags may not actually show up. Instead type &lt;code&gt;xm info&lt;/code&gt; and look for ‘hvm’ on the virt_caps line.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my hvm install, i’ll be installing Ubuntu 9.04 Desktop Linux.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I have copied the live CD ISO onto my XEN DOM0 and will be installing directly from the iso rather than burning the CD. I have also created a 10GB LVM logical volume to act as the disk for my new DOMU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manually creating a Xen DOMU instance</title>
      <link>http://www.kevssite.com/manually-creating-a-xen-domu-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.kevssite.com/manually-creating-a-xen-domu-instance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve followed my guide to installing xen from source then you might now be wondering how to create your first VM.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This guide will show you how to manually create and install a VM (known as a DOMU instance in Xen) without any additional tools such as virt-manager, virt-install or virsh. These tools can help the novice, but are quite limiting when it comes to the advance features of xen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For this example I’ll be installing CentOS5, but this should work for any red-hat based distro (please note there is a bug in fedora10 that stops it booting under xen). This example also uses the paravirtual kernel so it will work even if your CPU does not support AMD-V or intel-VT.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right, down to business. The first thing we need to do is create a file to user as the hard disk for the DOMU. There are other options for providing hard disks to a DOMU, and I’ll cover some of them in a later guide but for this install I’ll be using a file.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The command below will create an 8GB file that will be used as an 8GB drive. The whole file will be written to disk in one go so may take a short while to complete.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;code&gt;dd if=/dev/zero of=/xenimages/test01/disk1.img oflag=direct bs=1M count=8192&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Xen 3.3.1 from source on Debian 5.0 (Lenny)</title>
      <link>http://www.kevssite.com/installing-xen-33-from-source-on-debian-50-lenny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.kevssite.com/installing-xen-33-from-source-on-debian-50-lenny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is how I built my Xen server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First install Debian 5.0 (Lenny). This should also work on 4 (Etch) too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everything is done on the command line as root.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To build Xen from source you’ll need as fair number of dependencies. The easiest way to install them is by using the apt-get install command as below:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install bcc bin86 gawk bridge-utils iproute libcurl3 libcurl4-openssl-dev bzip2 module-init-tools transfig tgif texinfo pciutils-dev mercurial build-essential make gcc libc6-dev zlib1g-dev python python-dev python-twisted libncurses5-dev patch libvncserver-dev libsdl-dev libjpeg62-dev&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you installed the 64bit version of Debian then you’ll also need gcc-multilib for the compile to work:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install gcc-multilib&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
